Register of the Allan E. Goodman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1976-1996 INCREMENTS, 1950-1982, undated (Boxes 108-130, 135)
  - PRINTED MATTER, 1950-1973, undated (Boxes 122-130, 135)
    - United States Selective Service System, Registrants Processing Manual, 1972
    - The Viet Cong Infrastructure: Modus Operandi of Selected Political Cadres, 1968
    - Vietnam Studies Coordinating Group Bulletin, number 1, 1973 February
    - Webb, Eugene J., "A Review of Social Science Research in Vietnam with Procedural Recommendations for Future Research in Insurgent Settings,", 1968 December
- VISUAL MATERIAL, 1970-1971, undated (Box 130, Photo file, Oversize photo file)
  Contains photographs, a street map of Saigon, and Vietnamese political cartoons.
  - Autographed portrait of Ellsworth Bunker, U.S. Ambassador to South Vietnam, 1970 (Envelope A)
  - Color aerial view of Vietnam, undated (Envelope B)
  - Group photo of participants of the U.S. Department of State Scholar-Diplomat Seminar for East Asian Affairs in Washington, D.C. with letter, 1970-1971 (Envelope C)
    Also included are a pocket-sized portraits of Allan E. Goodman and Sok Thong Doeung, Director of the Research Department at the Technical University of Phnom Penh.
  - 7 prints of Lam Son Square, Saigon, with explanatory letter, 1970 (Envelope D)
    Also includes 23 negatives and 1 contact sheet.
  - 32 photos of missiles, airplanes, radar installations, and various scenes at headquarters and outlying posts of the North American Air Defense Command, undated (Envelope E)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes captions.
  - 2 watercolor paintings of scenes of daily life in a South Vietnamese village, undated (Envelope mF)
  - Mounted street map of Saigon, undated (Envelope mG)
  - Vietnamese political cartoons, circa 1968 (Box 130)
    Pencil and ink sketches depicting Vietnamese politics. Contains a description of each cartoon and captions in Vietnamese.
- FORMERLY CLOSED MATERIAL, 1960-1978 (Boxes 130-132)
  Contains material closed prior to 2015. Includes material related to the Republic of Vietnam's Armed Forces and research for some of Goodman's published works. Goodman's original file names have been preserved.
  - Army of the Republic of Vietnam (ARVN) input to International Security Affairs (ISA)/East Asian and Pacific Affairs (EAP): Summary and reform priorities, undated (Box 130)
  - "The Hour Is Late: A Conversation with Dr. Phan quang Dan,", 1969
    Contains a summary of an interview Goodman conducted with Dr. Dan and a letter regarding the summary.
  - "No More Vietnams"
    Materials for what was later renamed The Lost Peace.
    - Book photographs, circa 1968-1976
    - South Vietnam maps, 1968
    - Section materials, undated (Box 131)
  - Republic of Vietnam Armed Forces (RVNAF), 1960-1974, undated
    - Draft of report on RVNAF Officer Corps, undated
    - Political Structure
      - Comparative military organizations (VC/NVA), undated
      - Field grade officers, undated
      - General officer power structure, 1968-1969
      - Generals circa 1967-1971, 1968-1974
      - Military academies - Source of skills and futures, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1968-1974
      - Organization (TO/E), 1968, undated
      - Politics and government, 1960-1969
      - Pre 1963 power structure, undated
      - Social/political profiles, undated
      - Thieu's shift to Ky struggle - Military implications, 1968
  - United States Department of State, Viet-Nam Information Notes, 1967-1968
  - United States Military Assistance Command, "Big Mack Evaluation: Field Research in Binh Duong and Chuong Thien Provinces," photocopy, circa 1970
  - United States Mission in Vietnam, Viet-Nam Documents and Research Notes, 1968-1974 (Box 132)
    Contains documents 36-37, 74, 81, 88, 92, 107, 109, 115, and 116. See also Printed Matter in 1976-1996 Increments.
  - 12 notebooks, circa 1978
    Contains Goodman's handwritten notes regarding the Vietnam Negotiations. Most likely created in preparation for The Lost Peace: America's Search for a Negotiated Settlement of the Vietnam War.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, circa 1969 (Box 132)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 December release of records, circa 1969
    Contains correspondence, notes, and portions of documents related to the current state of South Vietnam. Also included is a summary of an interview with a doctor from Gia Dinh Province about the current conditions in the area.
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1967, 1971, 1974 (Boxes 133-134)
  Contains two sets of data related to Goodman's research on migration to Saigon and a poster.
  - Computer printouts, 1971, 1974
    Computer printouts of data used for a study entitled "The Dynamics of Migration to Saigon, 1964-1972," by Allan E. Goodman and Lawrence M. Franks.
    - Asian Survey Predictions: Factor Analysis, 1971 (Box 133)
    - SEADAG Project summary statistics, 1974 (Boxes 133-134)
  - Poster, "Miễn Nam Dại Thắng,", 1967 (Box 134)